

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · SYSTEM SOFWARE PROFESSION

Via Privata Giancarlo Puecher, 9, 20127 Milano MI, Italy

□ (+39) 351-6822452 | ■ anchi.liu@mail.polimi.it | ★ tigercosmos.xyz | □ tigercosmos | □ liuanchi

Summary _

Liu is a software engineer, and he is active in open source communities with the ID @tigercosmos. He is a master student of Computer Science at National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University (NYCU), Taiwan, and he is currently exchanging at Polytechnic University of Milan. He earned a B.S. degree in Bio-Industrial Mechatronics Engineering from National Taiwan University (NTU) in 2019. His research interests mainly focus on system software and high-performance programming. He loves sharing. He teaches coding, writes articles, and gives talks. He also participates in many open-source projects. He believes sharing makes the world a better place.

Education

National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University (NYCU)

Hsinchu, Taiwan

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2019 - Aug. 2022

- Thesis: Offloading Framework for Parallel Web Applications
- Previous school name: National Chiao Tung University (NCTU)

Polytechnic University of Milan

Milan, Italy

M.S. EXCHANGE PROGRAM IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2021 - Feb. 2022

National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

B.S. IN BIO-INDUSTRIAL MECHATRONICS ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2019

Work Experience

National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University

Hsinchu, Taiwan

TEACHING ASSISTANCE

2019 - 2021

- Parallel Programming (Spring 2021, Fall 2020). Won the NYCU excellent teaching assistants awards in the academic year of 2020
- Numerical Software Development (Spring 2021, Fall 2020, Spring 2020, Fall 2019)

National Center for High-Performance Computing

Hsinchu, Taiwan

RESEARCH INTERN

Jul 2020 - Mar 2021

· Built a full-stack system for neural architecture search via Angular, Express, Flask and MySQL

Skymizer Taipei, Taiwan

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Feb 2019 – Jun 2019

• Developed unit tests at variant levels for the C backed-end of the Open Neural Network Compiler (ONNC).

CloudMosa, Inc. Taipei, Taiwan

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- Developed the module of "Download to Cloud" on the Puffin browser, including a Python backend to connect clouds APIs and modifications for the Puffin core.
- Developed UI for the Puffin browser.

Delta Electronic, Inc.

Taipei, Taiwan

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

• Designed full-stack system via Angular, Ant Design, Express and MongoDB with complete unit tests at variant levels.

Fusion\$360 Software Engineering Intern

Taipei, Taiwan

• Designed and developed a frontend service with Angular.

Nov 2016 - Jul 2017

Developed crawlers of news and patents from many countries (Taiwan, Europe, U.S) in Java.